tipjoy.com 2009-04-20

# tipjoy | privacy policy

sign in | sign up | make money | search  

* * *

## Privacy policy

By using Tipjoy, you are agreeing to the collection and use of your personal information as described below. We will notify all active accounts of any significant changes to this policy. 

Tipjoy is founded on the principles of making it easy for people to give money to things they love online. Part of Tipjoy’s mission is to help its users find new content they’ll love via recommendations, top tip rankings, and friend tracking. We know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy very seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our privacy policy. 

This Privacy Policy covers Tipjoy’s treatment of personal information that we gather when you are on the Tipjoy website and when you use Tipjoy services, including the Tipjoy button. This policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Tipjoy does not own or control, or to individuals that Tipjoy does not employ or manage, including but not limited to the sites which choose to display Tipjoy button(s), or to content which is being tipped. 

### Cookies

When you sign into Tipjoy, a cookie is sent to your computer that contains an identification number that is unique to the computer you are using. 

This cookie enables us to keep you signed into Tipjoy on this computer until you explicitly press the “sign out” button located in the top-right area of the Tipjoy site. This way you will be able to give money to anything you like, quickly and easily, while you browse the internet. 

As long as you are signed into Tipjoy, any press of the Tipjoy button anywhere you see it on any site, or use of our tip-submission field, will result in the transfer of some amount of money from your account to the money receiver. 

Protect against unauthorized access to your Tipjoy account by signing out once you have finished using a shared computer. Doing so will expire the cookie on that machine. 

### What information does Tipjoy collect?

We only collect personal information that is relevant to the purpose of our website, in order to provide you with a customized experience. We receive and store all information you enter on our website or provide to us in any other way, including through the Tipjoy button and feedback page. In order to give money to something, you must provide us with an email address. We will record the date and time your account was created, and the amount of money you have in your account at all times. We also record what you have given and how much you have given each item. Other optional account information which we collect includes your username and your friend list. 

We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. This includes certain "traffic data" on server logs from your browser including your IP address, Tipjoy cookie information, the page you requested, and any browser specific information. Tipjoy uses this traffic data to help diagnose problems with its servers, analyze trends and administer the website. 

### Sharing of your Tipjoy account information

Because Tipjoy enables people to discover and share content they love with one another, information about the people who use Tipjoy is an integral part of the Tipjoy experience. We will neither rent nor sell your personal information to anyone. We will never look at your individual data unless you are having technical difficulties, it is required by law, or it is necessary to maintain our system. We will share your personal information only as described below: 

  1. **Social sharing of giving history** Your giving history is public by default. You may change this anytime in your Account Settings. Tipjoy allows other users to see your giving history, provided it is set to "public" in your Account Settings.
  2. **Friend search** The email address that you submit upon registration and your username will be searchable by other Tipjoy users who know you by your email address or Tipjoy username. 
  3. **API** Tipjoy will allow third parties access to all Tipjoy data that is already publicly available through the Tipjoy website. 
  4. **Syndication** Tipjoy allows for the RSS syndication of all of its public content within the Tipjoy website, including RSS syndication of your giving history, provided it is set to "public" in your Account Settings. Your giving history is public by default. You may change this anytime in your Account Settings.
  5. **Business Transfers** In some cases, we may choose to buy or sell assets. In these types of transactions, user information is typically one of the business assets that is transferred. Moreover, if Tipjoy, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred. 
  6. **To recipient** Tipjoy may provide your contact info to the person/people to whom you have money.

### Tipjoy email communications

Tipjoy is very concerned about your privacy and we will never provide your email address to a third party. You may receive notification emails from Tipjoy which inform you of actions (e.g. when someone has tipped you) that have been performed through the Tipjoy service and/or on the Tipjoy site. In addition, you may receive system emails (e.g. those regarding forgotten user passwords, emails reminding you to pay your bill), emails sent by Tipjoy on behalf of other Tipjoy members, and legal notices (e.g. updates to our policies) from us as long as you have a Tipjoy account. 

### Children under 18 years of age

You must be 13 years and older to register to use the Tipjoy website. As a result, Tipjoy does not specifically collect information about children. If we learn that Tipjoy has collected information from a child under the age of 13, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. We recommend that minors between the ages of 13 and 18 ask and receive their parents' permission before using Tipjoy or sending information about themselves or anyone else over the Internet. 

### Canceling your account

You may request deletion of your Tipjoy account by emailing us at founders@tipjoy.com
